A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Penitentiary, 1796-1991 (bulk 1906-1970)
Library of Virginia
- Series IV. Office of the Superintendent, 1869-1991 (bulk 1908-1970)., Extent: 76.60 cubic feet of records and 19 volumes. (Box 391-572, 693 and Oversize Box 2., Volume 143-161.)
  - Series IV. Subseries B. General Correspondence, 1892-1991 (bulk 1908-1970). (Box 391-484.)
    - Series IV.B.I. Superintendent B.W. Lynn, 1892-1896. (Box 391-394.)
      Bushrod W. Lynn was born in Loudoun County in 1842. During the Civil War, he enlisted as a private in Co. H. 1st Regt. Va. Cav., also known as the Loudoun Light Horse, and fought at the 1st Battle of Manassas. On Feb, 28, 1863, he was appointed ordnance sergeant and ordered to report to the Richmond defenses. Lynn was assigned to Battery No. 9 in April 1863, and later as assistant inspector of the Laboratory Dept., Richmond Arsenal. He also became assistant superintendent of the laboratory on Sept. 21, 1864. After the war, Lynn returned to Loudoun County to work on his farm. He entered the realm of politics and was elected Superintendent of the State Penitentiary three times serving from 1892 to 1898. He was also elected for two terms in the 11th Senatorial District of the State Senate in 1905. Lynn married Frances Hope Allen, daughter of Russell W. Allen of Richmond, on March 5, 1863. The couple had 4 sons and 2 daughters. His wife died in 1908 and he remarried in 1909 to Columbia Foster Van Deventer. He died on Oct. 17, 1917 in Los Angeles, Ca. and is buried in Hollywood Cemetery.
      - Index to Subjects; Joe Adams - Joseph R. Anderson (Box 391, Folder 1)
      - Joseph R. Anderson - C.G. Burton (Box 391, Folder 2)
      - W.E. Caldwell and Co. - W.P. Fortune (Box 391, Folder 3)
      - W.P. Fortune - R.S. Glinn (Box 391, Folder 4)
      - G.G. Gooch (Gooch and Waugh) - Governor's Office (Box 391, Folder 5)
      - Governor's Office - L.C. Hughes (Box 391, Folder 6)
      - Dr. Rolfe E. Hughes (Box 392, Folder 1)
      - John L. Hurt - Jas. D. Moncure (Box 392, Folder 2)
      - Dr. T.N.W. Morris (Gooch and Waugh) (Box 392, Folder 3)
      - Dr. T.N.W. Morris (Gooch and Waugh) - Secretary of the Commonwealth (Box 392, Folder 4)
      - Frank Shepherd - Charles R. Wright (Box 392, Folder 5)
      - Clothing (Box 392, Folder 6)
      - Clothing (Box 393, Folder 1)
      - County Roads/Prisoners, Communications (Box 393, Folder 2)
      - County Roads/Prisoners, Communications (Box 393, Folder 3)
      - Escapes, Relating to (Box 393, Folder 4)
      - [Improvements] (Box 393, Folder 5)
      - State Farm (Box 393, Folder 6)
      - State Farm (Box 394, Folder 1)
      - State Farm (Box 394, Folder 2)
    - Series IV.B.II. Superintendents' George M. Helms, Samuel M. Bolling and Evan F. Morgan, 1898-1907. (Box 394.)
      Superintendents' George M. Helms, Samuel M. Bolling and Evan F. Morgan, correspondence, 1898-1907, are housed in one folder and are arranged alphabetically. Helms served as Superintendent from 1898-1904. Bolling served from 1904 until his resignation on 4 December 1905 (Bolling was elected clerk of Bedford County circuit court). The Board elected Evan F. Morgan as Superintendent to serve the remaining two years of Bolling's term. The Board re-elected Morgan in 1908 and he served until his death on 4 December 1909.
      - John F. Jacobs and Company, 1898. (Box 394, Folder 3)
      - Frazier and Tompkins, 1899. (Box 394, Folder 3)
      - State Penitentiary Hospital. (Box 394, Folder 3)
      - 1901 and undated. (Box 394, Folder 3)
      - J.L. Taliaferro, 10 June 1904. (Box 394, Folder 3)
      - Clock for Virginia State Penitentiary, 24 July 1905. (Box 394, Folder 3)
      - National Prison Association, 1907. (Box 394, Folder 3)
    - Series IV.B.III. Superintendent Evan F. Morgan, 1908-1909. (Box 395-399.)
      Superintendents Evan F. Morgan's correspondence, 1908-1909, are housed in four boxes. Correspondence for fiscal year 1908-1909 (October-September) are arranged by numbers assigned to topics and reverse chronological order therein. Subjects include: No. 6 Electrocutions/Electric chair- requests to witness executions, installation of electric chair by Adams Electric Company, Trenton, N.J., 30 March 1909 (b395, f1); No. 7 letters of application for positions at the Penitentiary, State Farm or State Convict Road Force (b395, f2, f3 and f4); No. 8 planning for the American Prison Association, annual meeting held in Richmond, 14-19 November 1908 (b395, f6); No. 12 Employment and complaints of Paroled Prisoners [paroled prisoners were placed with perspective employers] (b396, f3); No. 44 Parole (b397, f3-5) No. 105 Information About Prison (b398, f5) see 22 April 1909 letter concerning shoe contract; made 20 years ago; expires in 1913; and letter to State Board of Charities and Corrections, 30 January 1909, describing prison furniture (b398, f5).
      Evan F. Morgan was born in Brenham, Texas, about 1862. At an early age, he relocated with his family first to Botetourt County, Virginia, then to Roanoke County, Virginia. In about 1893, he moved to Richmond to take the position of assistant superintendant of the Virginia Penitentiary. Following the resignation of Samuel S. Bolling, Morgan was promoted to superintendent in 1905. With wife Susie P. Morgan, he had three daughters, Laura, Julia, and Edna, and one son, Persons. Morgan died on 5 December 1909, the result of an illness contracted while visiting Seattle for the annual meeting of the American Prison Association..
      - B.III.1. Fiscal Year 1908-1909 (October to September)
        - No. 6 - Electrocutions/Electric Chair. (Box 395, Folder 1)
        - No. 7 - Application for Positions (part one). (Box 395, Folder 2)
        - No. 7 - Application for Positions (part two). (Box 395, Folder 3)
        - No. 7 - Application for Positions (part three). (Box 395, Folder 4)
        - No. 8 - American Prison Association, 1908-1909. (Box 395, Folder 5)
        - No. 8 - American Prison Association, 1907-1908. (Box 395, Folder 6)
        - No. 9 - M.C. Clark. (Box 395, Folder 7)
        - No. 10 - Condition of Prisoners. (Box 396, Folder 1)
        - No. 11 - [unknown heading]. (Box 396, Folder 2)
        - No. 12 - Employment and Complaints of. (Box 396, Folder 3)
        - No. 13 - B.H. Davenport, Banks. (Box 396, Folder 4)
        - No. 14 - Thomas L. Wilcox. (Box 396, Folder 4)
        - No. 15 - Stewart Jail Works. (Box 396, Folder 5)
        - No. 16 - J.B. Evans. (Box 396, Folder 6)
        - No. 17 - Chas. Lassiter. (Box 396, Folder 6)
        - No. 18 - Visiting of Prisoners. (Box 396, Folder 7)
        - No. 19 - Blankets. (Box 396, Folder 8)
        - No. 20 - Howard J. Woodward. (Box 396, Folder 8)
        - No. 21 - Re-New Lamp Company. (Box 396, Folder 8)
        - No. 22 - Blood Hounds. (Box 396, Folder 8)
        - No. 23 - Robert L. Pennington, re. George R. Rutherford. (Box 396, Folder 8)
        - No. 24 - Price Paid for Labor. (Box 396, Folder 8)
        - No. 25 - Escaped Prisoners. (Box 396, Folder 9)
        - No. 26 - Charles Brant and John Brown Wanted. (Box 396, Folder 10)
        - No. 27 - Bill. (Box 396, Folder 10)
        - No. 28 - William Glover and William Watson. (Box 396, Folder 10)
        - No. 29 - National Chemical Company - Chemicals. (Box 396, Folder 10)
        - No. 30 - J.J. Lucas. (Box 396, Folder 10)
        - No. 31 - Statement of Henry Smith. (Box 396, Folder 10)
        - No. 32 - J.J. Lynch - Stone from State Farm for sidewalk. (Box 396, Folder 10)
        - No. 33 - Guards, Discharge of. (Box 396, Folder 11)
        - No. 34 - Commutations. (Box 396, Folder 12)
        - No. 35 - Convicts/Prisoners - bringing of to prison. (Box 396, Folder 13)
        - No. 36 - Nationality of Prisoners. (Box 396, Folder 14)
        - No. 37 - Prisoners, Writing of/Writing to Prisoners. (Box 396, Folder 15)
        - No. 38 - Violation of Parole. (Box 396, Folder 16)
        - No. 39 - Pardons (Box 397, Folder 1)
        - No. 40 - Resignations (Box 397, Folder 2)
        - No. 41 - Size of Hats (Box 397, Folder 2)
        - No. 42 - George Pennison. (Box 397, Folder 2)
        - No. 43 - Return of Prisoners. (Box 397, Folder 2)
        - No. 44 - Paroles, Information Regarding to (part one). (Box 397, Folder 3)
        - No. 44 - Paroles, Information Regarding to (part two). (Box 397, Folder 4)
        - No. 44 - Paroles, Information Regarding to (part three). (Box 397, Folder 5)
        - No. 45 - Prices. (Box 397, Folder 6)
        - No. 46 - Contributions. (Box 397, Folder 6)
        - No. 47 - Insurance. (Box 397, Folder 6)
        - No. 48 - Record, Requests for Prisoners. (Box 397, Folder 7)
        - No. 49 - Requests for Prisoners Signatures. (Box 397, Folder 8)
        - No. 50 - Transferring to Prison. (Box 397, Folder 9)
        - No. 51 - Number of Prisoners. (Box 397, Folder 9)
        - No. 52 - Medical Services. (Box 397, Folder 9)
        - No. 53 - Description of Prisoners. (Box 398, Folder 1)
        - No. 54 - Voting, Returning Home for. (Box 398, Folder 2)
        - No. 55 - Impeaching Evidence. (Box 398, Folder 2)
        - No. 56 - Holding of Prisoners. (Box 398, Folder 2)
        - No. 57 - Reward for Recapture. (Box 398, Folder 2)
        - No. 58 - Recommendations. (Box 398, Folder 2)
        - No. 59 - Insect Extermination. (Box 398, Folder 2)
        - No. 60 - Filing Cases. (Box 398, Folder 2)
        - No. 61 - Delay in Returning Prisoners. (Box 398, Folder 3)
        - No. 62 - Moving of Letter Box. (Box 398, Folder 3)
        - No. 63 - Sending Roy Shelton to Farm. (Box 398, Folder 3)
        - No. 64 - Catalogues. (Box 398, Folder 3)
        - No. 65 - Preventing Prisoners Escaping. (Box 398, Folder 3)
        - No. 66 - Reformatory, Sending Colored Boy to Instead of Prison; Reform School, Sending Colored Girl to. (Box 398, Folder 3)
        - No. 67 - Transportation of Prisoners, Routes used. (Box 398, Folder 3)
        - No. 68 - Clock, Main Hall Penitentiary. (Box 398, Folder 3)
        - No. 69 - [Money] Orders Drawn by Prisoners. (Box 398, Folder 3)
        - No. 70 - Meat. (Box 398, Folder 3)
        - No. 71 - Chairs. (Box 398, Folder 3)
        - No. 72 - Refusing Admittance Colored Priest. (Box 398, Folder 3)
        - No. 73 - Illness of Men. (Box 398, Folder 3)
        - No. 74 - Discharge List. (Box 398, Folder 3)
        - No. 75 - Telephone, Farm, Changing of. (Box 398, Folder 3)
        - No. 76 - Rules and Regulations, Copies of. (Box 398, Folder 3)
        - No. 77 - Convict Clothing, Purchase of. (Box 398, Folder 3)
        - No. 78 - Cement Bags, Disposition of. (Box 398, Folder 3)
        - No. 79 - Discharge Certificates (U.S.N.). (Box 398, Folder 3)
        - No. 81 - Furnishing of Men to A.A. Phaup for Road Work. (Box 398, Folder 3)
        - No. 82 - Gifts, Returning of. (Box 398, Folder 3)
        - No. 83 - Tobaccos. (Box 398, Folder 3)
        - No. 84 - Coal. (Box 398, Folder 3)
        - No. 85 - Lassiter-Withers Road Law. (Box 398, Folder 4)
        - No. 86 - Treatment Elbert Smith. (Box 398, Folder 4)
        - No. 87 - Letterheads and Envelopes, Cost of. (Box 398, Folder 4)
        - No. 88 - Raspberry Plants, Care of. (Box 398, Folder 4)
        - No. 89 - Discharging of Employees. (Box 398, Folder 4)
        - No. 90 - Christmas Checks. (Box 398, Folder 4)
        - No. 91 - Electric Light Carbons. (Box 398, Folder 4)
        - No. 92 - Prisoners from Norfolk City, July 1907 to December 1908. (Box 398, Folder 4)
        - No. 93 - Stripes, Woolen and Flannel. (Box 398, Folder 4)
        - No. 94 - Prisoners to Camps. (Box 398, Folder 4)
        - No. 95 - Mare, Purchase of. (Box 398, Folder 4)
        - No. 96 - Concrete Floor Dressing. (Box 398, Folder 4)
        - No. 97 - Furloughs. (Box 398, Folder 4)
        - No. 98 - Money Made by Prisoners. (Box 398, Folder 4)
        - No. 99 - Freight Charges on Boxes. (Box 398, Folder 4)
        - No. 101 - Payment for Escapes of Loaned Men. (Box 398, Folder 4)
        - No. 102 - Smallpox. (Box 398, Folder 4)
        - No. 103 - Highway Association of S.E. Virginia. (Box 398, Folder 4)
        - No. 104 - Parole Laws, Request for Copies. (Box 398, Folder 4)
        - No. 105 - Information about Prison. (Box 398, Folder 5)
        - No. 106 - Second Conviction Men. (Box 398, Folder 6)
        - No. 107 - Purification of Water. (Box 398, Folder 6)
        - No. 108 - Riot Guns. (Box 398, Folder 6)
        - No. 109 - [unknown]. (Box 398, Folder 6)
        - No. 110 - Sending Men to State Farm. (Box 398, Folder 6)
        - No. 111 - Prisoners Signing Deed. (Box 398, Folder 6)
        - No. 112 - Crime and Drunkenness. (Box 398, Folder 6)
        - No. 113 - Dinning. (Box 398, Folder 6)
        - No. 114 - Contracts. (Box 398, Folder 7)
        - No. 115 - Guards, Reappointment. (Box 398, Folder 7)
        - No. 116 - Introduction, J.T. Mastin. (Box 398, Folder 7)
        - No. 117 - Subscriptions. (Box 398, Folder 7)
        - No. 118 - Conviction Railroad Bill. (Box 398, Folder 7)
        - No. 119 - Debate. (Box 398, Folder 7)
        - No. 120 - Shade Trees on Belvidere Street. (Box 398, Folder 7)
        - No. 121 - Charities and Corrections. (Box 398, Folder 7)
        - No. 122 - General File. (Box 398, Folder 7)
      - B.III.2. General Files, 1909
        - General File (Box 399, Folder 1)
    - Series IV.B. IV. Superintendent J.B. Wood, 1910-1919. (Box 399-408.)
      Superintendent J.B. Wood's correspondence, 1910-1919, are housed in ten boxes. The correspondence are further divided by date: B.IV.1. 1910-1911; B.IV.2. Personal Correspondence, 1911; B.IV.3. 1914-1916; B.IV.4. 1916; B.IV.5. 1916-1917; B.IV.6. 1917-1919; and B.IV.7. Personal Correspondence, 1917-1919. Following the death of Superintendent Morgan on 4 December 1909, Assistant Superintendent Fred A. Lamb became acting superintendent until the Board of Directors could name a permanent replacement. On 10 January 1910 the Board elected James B. Wood as Superintendent. Wood was born on 2 April 1847 in Spotsylvania County. He later moved to Richmond where he served on the Board of Alderman. Wood served as Superintendent until he submitted his resignation on 4 May 1922 effective 15 May 1922. The Board appointed Wood special advisory agent for the state convict road force. Wood held this position until his death on 9 March 1929.
      - B.IV.1. 1910-1911. (Box 399-400.)
        Correspondence are arranged in reverse chronological order and by numbers assigned to topics; notable correspondence include: correspondence between paroled prisoners and the Superintendent about how they are getting along (see General Correspondence: Charles Miller, 18 August 1911; W.H. Reynolds, 8 August 1911; H.W. Herwig, 3 August 1911; Lemuel Summerall, 9 May 1911; Robert H. Diggs, 4136, 25 April 1911; Ben Parker, 8432, 12 April 1911; Andrew Burch, 9194, 11 April 1911; Joe Perry, 6733, 31 March 1911; Howard Shelor, 9154, 24 March 1911; William Hill, 16 March 1911; Mills W. Munford, 14 February 1911; J.W. Pooser, 9115, 11 February 1911; Ross Urquart, 12 January 1911; ); correspondence from prisoners' family members inquiring about their health and chance of parole; and correspondence inquiring about guard positions.
        - General Files, 1910. (Box 399, Folder 2)
        - General Files, 10 September 1911 to 1 May 1911. (Box 399, Folder 3)
        - General Files, 28 April 1911 to 6 April 1911. (Box 399, Folder 4)
        - General Files, 5 April 1911 to 10 March 1911. (Box 399, Folder 5)
        - General Files, 9 March 1911 to 17 February 1911. (Box 399, Folder 6)
        - General Files, 15 February 1911 to 6 February 1911. (Box 400, Folder 1)
        - General Files, 3 February 1911 to 24 January 1911. (Box 400, Folder 2)
        - General Files, 23 January 1911 to 12 January 1911. (Box 400, Folder 3)
        - General Files, 11 January 1911 to 2 January 1911. (Box 400, Folder 4)
        - No. 21 - [Parole], 1911. (Box 400, Folder 5)
      - B.IV.2. Personal Correspondence, 1911. (Box 400.)
        Personal Correspondence are housed in one folder and contains personal correspondence to Superintendent J.B. Wood.
        - January-August 1911. (Box 400, Folder 6)
      - B.IV.3. 1914-1916. (Box 401-404.)
        Correspondence are arranged by numbers assigned to topics. Notable topics include: No. 25 General Correspondence, children in penitentiary, 26 February 1916 (b401, f9); religious services at the penitentiary, 11 January 1916 (b401, f10); survey response about Penitentiary salaries, duties and organization, 20 November 1915 (b401, f11); correspondence with Chicago Police Department describing the buildings at the Penitentiary, 13 November 1915 (b401, f11); correspondence with A.J.G. Wells, Warden, Kentucky State Reformatory, describing prison labor at the Penitentiary, 27 October 1915 (b401, f11); letter to James E. Brockwell listing Penitentiary employees and salaries, 7 April 1915 (b402, f4); correspondence with P.J. McDonnell, Supt., New York State Reformatory describing rules and life in the Penitentiary, 20 February 1915 (b402, f4); and correspondence with Mary Morse, 11083, re: children in penitentiary, 18 January 1915 (b402, f6); No. 38 State Lime Grinding Plant consists primarily of correspondence between State Lime Grinding Plant Superintendent. J.E. Vance and J.B. Woods. Topics include broken equipment, supplies, bills, plant operations, installation of equipment, location of plant, hiring superintendent of State Lime Grinding Plant; [State Convict Road Force], Notable correspondence include: statement showing number of men on Roads (white, colored, and jailmen), number of trusties, cost of maintenance, escapes, 22 July 1914 (b403, f8).
        - No. 1 - [Requests for Prisoner Records], 1914-1916. (Box 401, Folder 1)
        - No. 11 - [Prisoner Escapes], 1915. (Box 401, Folder 2)
        - No. 11 - [Prisoner Escapes], 1915-1916. (Box 401, Folder 3)
        - No. 12 - [Auditor of Public Accounts], 1915. (Box 401, Folder 4)
        - No. 13 - [Coal], 1911, 1914-1915. (Box 401, Folder 5)
        - No. 17 - [Annual Reports], 1914-1916. (Box 401, Folder 6)
        - No. 20 - [Prisoner Inquiries], 1914-1916. (Box 401, Folder 7)
        - No. 22 - [Prisoner Information - Deaths], 1915-1916. (Box 401, Folder 8)
        - No. 25 - [General Correspondence](part one), 1914-1916. (Box 401, Folder 9)
        - No. 25 - [General Correspondence](part two), 1914-1916. (Box 401, Folder 10)
        - No. 25 - [General Correspondence](part three), 1914-1916. (Box 401, Folder 11)
        - No. 25 - [General Correspondence](part four), 1914-1916. (Box 402, Folder 1)
        - No. 25 - [General Correspondence](part five), 1914-1916. (Box 402, Folder 2)
        - No. 25 - [General Correspondence](part six), 1914-1916. (Box 402, Folder 3)
        - No. 25 - [General Correspondence](part seven), 1914-1916. (Box 402, Folder 4)
        - No. 25 - [General Correspondence](part eight), 1914-1916. (Box 402, Folder 5)
        - No. 25 - [General Correspondence](part nine), 1914-1916. (Box 402, Folder 6)
        - No. 26 - [Visiting Prisoners], 1914-1916. (Box 403, Folder 1)
        - No. 28 - [Prisoner Money], 1914-1916. (Box 403, Folder 2)
        - No. 33 - [Insurance], 1916. (Box 403, Folder 3)
        - No. 36 - [Prisoner Inquiries], 1915-1916. (Box 403, Folder 4)
        - No. 38 - [State Lime Grinding Plant] (part one),. (Box 403, Folder 5)
        - No. 38 - [State Lime Grinding Plant] (part two), 1912, 1914-1916. (Box 403, Folder 6)
        - No. 38 - [State Lime Grinding Plant] (part three), 1912, 1914-1916. (Box 403, Folder 7)
        - State Convict Road Force] (part one), 1914-1916. (Box 403, Folder 8)
        - State Convict Road Force] (part two), 1914-1916. (Box 404, Folder 1)
        - State Convict Road Force] (part three), 1914-1916. (Box 404, Folder 2)
        - State Convict Road Force] (part four), 1914-1916. (Box 404, Folder 3)
      - B.IV.4. 1916. (Box 404.)
        Correspondence are arranged alphabetically by subject including: requests for body of executed prisoner (b404, f4); pardon requests (b404, f6); and Prisoner Information-Deaths, 1916 (b404, f7).
        - Electrocutions, 1916. (Box 404, Folder 4)
        - Financial, 1916. (Box 404, Folder 5)
        - Pardon/Parole Requests, 1916. (Box 404, Folder 6)
        - Prisoner Information - Deaths, 1916. (Box 404, Folder 7)
        - Prisoner Inquiries, 1916. (Box 404, Folder 8)
        - Prisoner Rendition Requests, 1916. (Box 404, Folder 9)
        - Visiting Prisoners, 1916. (Box 404, Folder 10)
      - B.IV.5. 1916-1917. (Box 404-407.)
        General Correspondence are arranged by number and subjects include: prisoner information/inquiries, clemency requests, employment requests, and requests from Governor's Office for prisoner records. Notable documents include: No. 213 correspondence with William Colstep re: children born in penitentiary, 13 May 1916 (b406, f1); No. 216 correspondence with Prison Physician at New York's Sing Sing Prison re: Electrocutions, 13 May 1916 (b406, f1); and No. 266 correspondence with Senator G. Walter Mapp re: treatment of Mapp's friend, T.B. Mason, a prisoner who Wood watched over at Mapp's request, 31 May 1916 (b406, f2).
        - General Correspondence, No. 1 - No. 38. (Box 405, Folder 1)
        - General Correspondence, No. 39 - No. 71. (Box 405, Folder 2)
        - General Correspondence, No. 72 - No. 99. (Box 405, Folder 3)
        - General Correspondence, No. 100 - No. 132. (Box 405, Folder 4)
        - General Correspondence, No. 133 - No. 168. (Box 405, Folder 5)
        - General Correspondence, No. 169 - No. 206. (Box 405, Folder 6)
        - General Correspondence, No. 207 - No. 245. (Box 406, Folder 1)
        - General Correspondence, No. 246 - No. 284. (Box 406, Folder 2)
        - General Correspondence, No. 285 - No. 303. (Box 406, Folder 3)
        - Annual Report, 1916-1917. (Box 406, Folder 4)
        - Bloodhounds, 1917. (Box 406, Folder 5)
        - Electrocutions, 1916-1917. (Box 406, Folder 6)
        - Financial, 1916-1917. (Box 406, Folder 7)
        - Pardon/Parole Requests (part one). (Box 406, Folder 8)
        - Pardon/Parole Requests (part two). (Box 406, Folder 9)
        - Pardon/Parole Requests (part three). (Box 407, Folder 1)
        - Pardon/Parole Requests (part four). (Box 407, Folder 2)
        - Prisoner Information - Deaths (part one). (Box 407, Folder 3)
        - Prisoner Information - Deaths (part two). (Box 407, Folder 4)
        - Prisoner Inquiries (part one). (Box 407, Folder 5)
        - Prisoner Inquiries (part two). (Box 407, Folder 6)
        - Prisoner Rendition Requests, 1916-1917. (Box 407, Folder 7)
        - Visiting Prisoners, 1916-1917. (Box 407, Folder 8)
      - B.IV.6. 1917-1918-1919. (Box 408.)
        Correspondence are arranged alphabetically by subject including: pardon/parole requests, prisoner inquiries and prisoner deaths.
        - Prisoner Information - Insane, 1917. (Box 408, Folder 1)
        - Pardon/Parole Requests, 1917. (Box 408, Folder 2)
        - Prisoner Inquiries, 1918-1919. (Box 408, Folder 3)
        - Prisoner Rendition Requests, 1917. (Box 408, Folder 4)
        - [No. 14] Prisoner Deaths, 1917-1919. (Box 408, Folder 5)
        - Coal, 1917-1919. (Box 408, Folder 6)
        - Auditor of Public Accounts, undated. (Box 408, Folder 7)
        - [unidentified] (Box 408, Folder 8)
      - B.IV.7. Personal Correspondence, 1917-1978. (Box 408.)
        Personal Correspondence are arranged by assigned numbers. Contains correspondence with H.W. Melton, chief clerk of the State Convict Road Force, and a patient at the Catawba Sanatorium (A-149, 20 August 1918; A-152, 26 August 1918; A-155, 2 August 1918; A-156, 12 August 1918; A-160, 8 July 1918; A-161, 18 July 1918; A-165, 21 June 1918).
        - A-145 to A-183. (Box 408, Folder 9)